[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Who is known as the 'Lady of the Lamp'?",
    "options": [
      "Sorojini Naidu",
      "Hellen Killer",
      "Madame Teresa",
      "Florence Nightingale"
    ],
    "answer": "Florence Nightingale"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "For which of the following disciplines Nobel Prize is awarded?",
    "options": [
      "Literature, peace and Economices",
      "Physiology or Medicine",
      "Physices and Chemistry",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Lunar eclipse occurs on -",
    "options": [
      "A moonless day",
      "A full moon day",
      "A new moon day",
      "A half moon day"
    ],
    "answer": "A full moon day"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Which of the following ecosystems covers the largest area of the earth's surface ?",
    "options": [
      "Desert Ecosystem",
      "Mountain Ecosystem",
      "Marine Ecosystem",
      "Fresh water Ecosystem"
    ],
    "answer": "Marine Ecosystem"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "In Cricket game the length of the pitch between the two wickets is -",
    "options": ["21 yards", "22 yards", "23 yards", "24 yards"],
    "answer": "22 yards"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "IMF is the result of",
    "options": [
      "Brettonwood Conference",
      "Hawana Conference",
      "Rome Conference",
      "Geneva Conference"
    ],
    "answer": "Brettonwood Conference"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Dengue fever is spread by--",
    "options": [
      "Aedes aegypti mosquito",
      "Common House flies",
      "Anophilies mosquito",
      "Rats and squirrels"
    ],
    "answer": "Aedes aegypti mosquito"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "International Court of Justice-এর সদর দপ্তর কোথায় অবস্থিত?",
    "options": [
      "যুক্তরাষ্ট্রের নিউ ইয়র্কে",
      "সুইজারল্যান্ডের বার্নে",
      "কানাডার অটোয়ায়",
      "নেদারল্যান্ডসের দ্য হেগে"
    ],
    "answer": "নেদারল্যান্ডসের দ্য হেগে"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "√169 is equal to -",
    "options": ["15", "13", "11", "17"],
    "answer": "13"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Badminton is the national sport of -",
    "options": ["Nepal", "Malaysia", "Scotland", "China"],
    "answer": "Malaysia"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "EURO is the currency of -",
    "options": ["Africa", "Europe", "Asia", "America"],
    "answer": "Europe"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Photosynthesis takes place in -",
    "options": [
      "All parts of the plants",
      "Roots of the plant",
      "Stems of the plants",
      "Green parts of the plants"
    ],
    "answer": "Green parts of the plants"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "The term PC means -",
    "options": [
      "Personal computer",
      "Professional computer",
      "Private computer",
      "Prime computer"
    ],
    "answer": "Personal computer"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Fill in the blank of the following sentence with the right form of verb. if I _____ a king!",
    "options": ["shall be", "am", "were", "was"],
    "answer": "were"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "Tiger: Zoology :: Mars : __",
    "options": ["Astronomy", "Astrology", "Crytology", "Telescopy"],
    "answer": "Astronomy"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "'Maiden speech' means--",
    "options": ["Late speech", "Early speech", "Final speech", "First speech"],
    "answer": "First speech"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "N.B stands for -",
    "options": ["Non bearing", "Nota bene", "Note before", "No bar"],
    "answer": "Nota bene"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "What is the masculine gender of 'mare' ?",
    "options": ["Mermaid", "Stallion", "Bear", "Dog"],
    "answer": "Stallion"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "'Botany' is to 'plants' as 'Zoology’ is to__.",
    "options": ["animals", "flowers", "trees", "dear"],
    "answer": "animals"
  }
]
